<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving
and Interchange DTD v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd">

<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" dtd-version="1.2" article-type="other">

<front>


<article-meta>


<title-group>
<article-title>ESS 330 Project Proposals</article-title>
</title-group>

<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes">
<name>
<surname>Aburomia</surname>
<given-names>Leila</given-names>
</name>
<string-name>Leila Aburomia</string-name>

<xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor-1">&#x002A;</xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Perez</surname>
<given-names>Aldair</given-names>
</name>
<string-name>Aldair Perez</string-name>

</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Goodhardt</surname>
<given-names>Noah</given-names>
</name>
<string-name>Noah Goodhardt</string-name>

</contrib>
</contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor-1"></corresp>
</author-notes>









<history></history>






</article-meta>

</front>

<body>
<p>📩 *Corresponding author: Leila Aburomia</p>
<sec id="section">
  <title>1.</title>
  <p>completed by: Leila Aburomia</p>
  <sec id="title">
    <title>Title:</title>
    <p>Beavers’ Impact on Water Quality</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="justification">
    <title>Justification:</title>
    <p>Beavers have the ability to modify ecosystems to meet their
    ecological needs, profoundly impacting hydrology, geomorphology,
    ecology, and society. Known as ecosystem engineers, beavers and
    their dam building activities significantly alter water flow quality
    (Brazier
    (<xref alt="2020" rid="ref-Brazier2020" ref-type="bibr">2020</xref>)).
    This project with use R to analyze how beavers influence water
    quality parameters such as dissolved oxygen, temperature, turbidity,
    and nutrient levels. In degraded environments, beavers’ dam building
    can improve both physical and biological diversity (Law
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-Law2016" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>)).
    This diversity is essential for the functionality of many stream
    types (Law
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-Law2016" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>)).
    Additionally, research has shown that beaver dams can help mitigate
    climatic hydrological extremes through their impacts on water
    residence time and nutrient fluxes (Dewey
    (<xref alt="2022" rid="ref-Dewey2022" ref-type="bibr">2022</xref>)).
    Understanding how their activities influence water quality is
    crucial for ecosystem management, conservation, and climate
    resilience. Local beaver motifications can help inform hydrology
    decisions to increase the health and functionality of our
    watersheds.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="research-objective">
    <title>Research Objective:</title>
    <p>The specific objective that I aim to achieve is how beaver
    activity influences water quality parameters. Possible hypothesizes
    may include; beaver-occupied streams have lower turbidity due to
    sediment trapping, beaver ponds reduce dissolved oxygen compared to
    fast-flowing streams, beaver activity increases nutrient levels due
    to organic matter decomposition, and beaver ponds act as temperature
    buffers, reducing extreme fluctuations.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="proposed-methods">
    <title>Proposed Methods:</title>
    <p>This study will be done on a spatial scale and investigate how
    water quality parameters change depending on the presence of
    beavers. Beaver presence data can be found through Colorado Natural
    Heritage Program. They have a Colorado River basin Dynamic Wetland
    Mapper that includes beaver ponds.
    (https://csurams.maps.arcgis.com/apps/webappviewer/index.html?id=2fa3527926d2415d8ea0786838b712bd).
    Additionally, USGS has current water data for Colorado that includes
    many water quality parameters
    (https://waterdata.usgs.gov/co/nwis/rt). Variables we will use are
    beaver presence and water quality parameters such as nutrients and
    physical values. For our data analysis we will first filter data for
    beaver vs non- beaver sites. Our statistical tests will include
    summary(), and ggplot2 to visualize distributions. Then we will
    create boxplots to test relationships between beaver presence and
    water quality parameters. We will use the Shapiro-Wilk Test for
    Normality to test the distribution of the data and use T-Tests to
    compare means between the two groups (beaver vs. non-beaver).</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="expected-outcomes">
    <title>Expected Outcomes:</title>
    <p>I expect to find turbidity lower in beaver - occupied sites which
    suggests that beaver dams trap sediment and improve water quality. I
    would also expect DO to be lower in beaver ponds, indicating that
    shower water movement and organic decay reduces oxygen levels.
    Lastly, I expect to find nutrient levels higher in beaver ponds,
    showing that organic matter accumulation influences nutrient
    cycling.</p>
  </sec>
</sec>
<sec id="section-1">
  <title>2.</title>
  <p>completed by: Leila Aburomia</p>
  <sec id="title-1">
    <title>Title:</title>
    <p>Climate Change Impacts on Peak Flow Events in the Upper Colorado
    River Basin</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="justification-1">
    <title>Justification:</title>
    <p>This project is significant because it addresses critical
    challenges within climate change, hydrology, water management, and
    environmental sustainability. Climate change impacts of hydrology is
    an understudied topic. Research has shown that climate change caused
    alterations in the colorado river basin are likely occurring now and
    will increase over the next several decades (Nash
    (<xref alt="1993" rid="ref-Nash1993" ref-type="bibr">1993</xref>)).
    The Upper Colorado River Basin is one of the most vital watersheds
    in the western United States. The Colorado River supplies water to
    27 million people across seven U.S states and Mexico (Gao
    (<xref alt="2011" rid="ref-Gao2011" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>)).
    In the Colorado River Basin, projected runoff changes are impacted
    by snow cover change, temperature, and precipitation (Gao
    (<xref alt="2011" rid="ref-Gao2011" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>)).
    The basin is especially sensitive to shifts in climate due to
    vulnerable discharge, which is exacerbated by it’s semiarid
    environment. Given the basin’s increasing population, need for
    water, and warming climate, variations in the Colorado River flows
    are critically important.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="research-objective-1">
    <title>Research Objective:</title>
    <p>The project objective is to analyze how climate change is
    altering peak flow events in the Upper Colorado watershed using
    historical observations and future climate projections. The research
    question is as follows, How is climate change affecting the
    magnitude and timing of peak flow events in the Upper Colorado
    watershed, and what are the projected changes under future climate
    scenarios? The hypothesis is that Future climate projections
    indicate significant changes in peak flow magnitude, timing, or
    frequency under warming scenarios.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="proposed-methods-1">
    <title>Proposed Methods:</title>
    <p>Using data from USGS Water Information System
    (https://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis?) we will extract data about
    historical precipitation and temperature, and future temperature and
    precipitation projections using the climateR package. First we will
    identify annual peak flow events from the USGS data and use
    Mann-Kendall trend tests (trend package) to detect
    increasing/decreasing trends. Then we will compare correlations
    between peak flows with precipitation and temperature trends. Next
    we will use the CMIP6 climate projections for precipitation and
    temperature (climateR package) and apply hydrological models for
    stream flow simulations to predict how magnitudes and frequencies
    may change under warming climate conditions. This project will be
    carried on a temporal scale.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="expected-outcomes-1">
    <title>Expected Outcomes:</title>
    <p>Based on data, expected outcomes will include historical analysis
    of peak flow trends in the Upper Colorado, and projected changes in
    peak flows under different warming conditions. These findings are
    important because understanding how climate change is affecting peak
    flow events in the Upper Colorado watershed has critical
    implications for water management, ecosystem health, and flood risk
    assessments and mitigation.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="section-2">
    <title>3.</title>
    <p>completed by: Aldair Perez</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="title-2">
    <title>Title:</title>
    <p>The Popularity of Renewable and Non-Renewable Energy Sources in
    the U.S.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="justification-2">
    <title>Justification:</title>
    <p>This project aims to understand how much of the U.S is coming
    from renewable energy and non-renewable energy The findings will
    present us exactly where the energy comes from, like a percentage
    from a source. We are currently living in a unique time where we are
    seeing the emergence of renewables (slow development, incentives,
    and technological problems) and the continued use and advancements
    of non-renewables, like fracking shale gas (Furlan
    (<xref alt="2017" rid="ref-Furlan2017" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>)).
    The rise of renewables and making non-renewables cleaner/efficient
    is due in part to global warming. According to empirical research,
    90% of CO2 emissions are from fossil fuels (Greiner
    (<xref alt="2013" rid="ref-Greiner2013" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>)).
    If we want to mitigate the effects of global warming, we should
    implement cleaner solutions to our energy resources, like efficient
    cars/appliances and fracking regulations.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="research-objective-2">
    <title>Research Objective:</title>
    <p>We will identify how much each renewable and non-renewable energy
    contributes to the amount of energy used in the U.S.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="proposed-methods-2">
    <title>Proposed Methods:</title>
    <p>We are going to look for datasets that have the amount of energy
    produced by each source of energy. The timeline should be recent, so
    the maximum is looking at the energy production during the past 10
    years. The country that will be used is the United States of
    America. We will calculate the total energy and find the percentage
    each source contributes to the total energy produced. The data used
    may be from this website: Opendata - U.S. Energy Information
    Administration (EIA)</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="expected-outcomes-2">
    <title>Expected Outcomes:</title>
    <p>We are looking at the percentage used to give us an understanding
    of the popularity (or lack of popularity) for each source. The
    significance of this is to understand where energy is coming from
    since we are in a time where society is becoming more
    environmentally conscious.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="section-3">
    <title>4.</title>
    <p>completed by: Aldair Perez</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="title-3">
    <title>Title:</title>
    <p>The Rise and Impact of H5N1 Cases in the U.S</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="justification-3">
    <title>Justification:</title>
    <p>This project aims to understand the impacts of bird flu in
    domesticated animals, like chickens and cows. With the rise of
    prices of related foods, like beef, eggs, and chickens, this is
    causing food supply problems. In 2020, there’s an outbreak of avian
    influenza (H5N1) and it has spread to not only chickens, but cows
    (Abbasi
    (<xref alt="2024" rid="ref-Abbasi2024" ref-type="bibr">2024</xref>)).
    This is an obvious cause of concern to the food supply and human
    health. According to USDA, over 37 million poultry have died,
    chicken breast prices rose 27%, and egg prices rose 45% (Hunter
    (<xref alt="2022" rid="ref-Hunter2022" ref-type="bibr">2022</xref>)).
    This recent outbreak, along with COVID-19, has put pressure to human
    and animal health as well as the state of the economy. Thus, it’s
    vital that we have a good understanding of the virus, the numbers,
    and how to respond to this outbreak.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="research-objective-3">
    <title>Research Objective:</title>
    <p>We will identify the cases and deaths of the H5N1 virus towards
    animals like cows and chickens in the U.S.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="proposed-methods-3">
    <title>Proposed Methods:</title>
    <p>We will look for datasets that give us information as to who has
    the virus infected, the cases, and deaths from the hosts (likely
    chickens, cows, and humans). Since this is a recent outbreak, we
    will look at the data from the past 5 years. We will be looking at
    the cases here in the U.S. We will find the dataset from these
    links: H5 Bird Flu: Current Situation | Bird Flu | CDC, USDA
    Reported H5N1 Bird Flu Detections in Poultry | Bird Flu | CDC, Avian
    influenza</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="expected-outcomes-3">
    <title>Expected Outcomes:</title>
    <p>We are looking at how many cases and deaths the virus has had on
    chickens, cows, and people. The significance of this is to
    understand the extent to which the flu has impacted the
    populations.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="section-4">
    <title>5.</title>
    <p>completed by: Noah Goodhart</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="title-4">
    <title>Title:</title>
    <p>Urban Green Space Accessibility and Its Role in Sustainable City
    Development</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="justification-4">
    <title>Justification:</title>
    <p>Urban green spaces are critical for sustainable cities, improving
    biodiversity, mental health, and climate resilience (Organization
    (<xref alt="2016" rid="ref-WHO2016" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>)).
    However, unequal access to green spaces worsens environmental
    injustice, particularly in low-income neighborhoods (Rigolon
    (<xref alt="2018" rid="ref-Rigolon2018" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>)).
    This project assesses whether income levels correlate with green
    space accessibility in U.S. cities, supporting the UN Sustainable
    Development Goal (SDG) 11 for inclusive, sustainable
    urbanization.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="research-objective-4">
    <title>Research Objective:</title>
    <p>Objective: Evaluate the relationship between neighborhood income
    levels and green space coverage and assess if there is a significant
    correlation between the two.</p>
    <p>Hypothesis: Lower-income neighborhoods will have significantly
    less green space per capita than higher-income areas.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="proposed-methods-4">
    <title>Proposed Methods:</title>
    <p>Datasets:</p>
    <list list-type="order">
      <list-item>
        <p>Green space data: NASA’s MODIS NDVI (Normalized Difference
        Vegetation Index) via the MODIStsp R package.</p>
      </list-item>
      <list-item>
        <p>Income &amp; demographic data: U.S. Census Bureau’s American
        Community Survey (ACS) via the tidycensus R package. Scope: 5
        major U.S. cities (2015–2020). Analysis:</p>
      </list-item>
    </list>
    <p>· Spatial mapping with sf and ggplot2.</p>
    <p>· Correlation tests (Pearson’s r) between median income and NDVI
    values.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="expected-outcomes-4">
    <title>Expected Outcomes:</title>
    <p>We expect a positive correlation between income and green space
    access. The results could guide equitable urban sustainability
    planning.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="section-5">
    <title>6.</title>
    <p>completed by: Noah Goodhart</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="title-5">
    <title>Title:</title>
    <p>Drought Severity and Agricultural Water Use in Colorado</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="justification-5">
    <title>Justification:</title>
    <p>Colorado’s water resources are under increasing stress due to
    climate change, with the 2002–2022 period marking the driest two
    decades in 1,200 years (Williams
    (<xref alt="2022" rid="ref-Williams2022" ref-type="bibr">2022</xref>)).
    Agriculture accounts for ~80% of the state’s water use, yet drought
    adaptation strategies (e.g., improved irrigation) remain unevenly
    adopted (CWCB
    (<xref alt="n.d." rid="ref-CWCB2021" ref-type="bibr">n.d.</xref>)).
    This project evaluates whether drought severity correlates with
    reduced agricultural water withdrawals, supporting sustainable water
    management under SDG 6.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="research-objective-5">
    <title>Research Objective:</title>
    <p>Objective: Test if drought severity (PDSI) predicts changes in
    agricultural water use in Colorado. Hypothesis: Counties with severe
    drought (PDSI ≤ −3) will show greater declines in agricultural water
    withdrawals compared to less-affected counties.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="proposed-methods-5">
    <title>Proposed Methods:</title>
    <p>Datasets (all R-friendly): 1. Drought Data: Palmer Drought
    Severity Index (PDSI) for Colorado from NOAA (NCEI), accessed via
    rnoaa.</p>
    <list list-type="order">
      <list-item>
        <label>2.</label>
        <p>Water Use: Colorado’s Agricultural Water Use Data (CWCB)
        (CSV/Excel).</p>
      </list-item>
      <list-item>
        <label>3.</label>
        <p>Crop Data: USDA CropScape (Colorado-specific) via the FedData
        package.</p>
      </list-item>
    </list>
    <p>Scope: Colorado counties (2010–2020). Analysis:</p>
    <p>· Time-series regression (lm()) between PDSI and water
    withdrawals.</p>
    <p>· Spatial maps of drought vs. water use trends using
    ggplot2/sf.</p>
  </sec>
  <sec id="expected-outcomes-5">
    <title>Expected Outcomes:</title>
    <p>We anticipate counties with severe drought will show reduced
    agricultural water use, reflecting adaptation efforts. Results could
    guide policies to incentive water-efficient farming.</p>
  </sec>
</sec>
</body>

<back>
<ref-list>
  <title></title>
  <ref id="ref-Law2016">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Law</surname><given-names>McLean</given-names><suffix>A.</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Habitat engineering by beaver benefits aquatic biodiversity and ecosystem processes in agricultural streams</article-title>
      <publisher-name>Freshwater Biology</publisher-name>
      <publisher-loc>USA</publisher-loc>
      <year iso-8601-date="2016">2016</year>
      <volume>61</volume>
      <issue>4</issue>
      <uri>https://doi-org.ezproxy2.library.colostate.edu/10.1111/fwb.12721</uri>
      <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/fwb.12721</pub-id>
      <fpage>486</fpage>
      <lpage>499</lpage>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Brazier2020">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Brazier</surname><given-names>Puttock</given-names><suffix>R. E.</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Beaver: Nature’s ecosystem engineers</article-title>
      <publisher-name>WIREs Water</publisher-name>
      <publisher-loc>USA</publisher-loc>
      <year iso-8601-date="2020">2020</year>
      <volume>8</volume>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <uri>https://doi.org/10.1002/wat2.1494</uri>
      <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/wat2.1494</pub-id>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Dewey2022">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Dewey</surname><given-names>Fox</given-names><suffix>C.</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Beaver dams overshadow climate extremes in controlling riparian hydrology and water quality</article-title>
      <publisher-name>Nature Communications</publisher-name>
      <publisher-loc>USA</publisher-loc>
      <year iso-8601-date="2022">2022</year>
      <volume>13</volume>
      <issue>6509</issue>
      <uri>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-34022-0</uri>
      <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-34022-0</pub-id>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Gao2011">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>Vano</given-names><suffix>Y.</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Evaluating climate change over the colorado river basin using regional climate models</article-title>
      <publisher-name>Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="2011">2011</year>
      <volume>116</volume>
      <issue>D13</issue>
      <uri>https://doi.org/10.1029/2010JD015278</uri>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Nash1993">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Nash</surname><given-names>P. H.</given-names><suffix>L. L. &amp; Gleick</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>The colorado river basin and climatic change</article-title>
      <publisher-name>Pacific Institute for Studies in Development, Environment,; Security</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="1993">1993</year>
      <uri>http://www.onthecolorado.org/resources/ClimateDocs/NashGleick1993.pdf</uri>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Abbasi2024">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Abbasi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Bird flu outbreak in dairy cows is widespread, raising public health concerns</article-title>
      <publisher-name>JAmA</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
      <volume>331</volume>
      <issue>21</issue>
      <uri>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38718040/</uri>
      <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jama.2024.8886</pub-id>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Furlan2017">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Furlan</surname><given-names>C</given-names><suffix>C. &amp; Mortarino</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Forecasting the impact of renewable energies in competition with non-renewable sources</article-title>
      <publisher-name>Renewable; Sustainable Energy Reviews</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="2017">2017</year>
      <volume>81</volume>
      <uri>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2017.05.284</uri>
      <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.05.284</pub-id>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Greiner2013">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Greiner</surname><given-names>Grüne</given-names><suffix>A.</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Economic growth and the transition from non-renewable to renewable energy</article-title>
      <publisher-name>Environment; development economies</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="2013">2013</year>
      <volume>19</volume>
      <issue>4</issue>
      <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1017/S1355770X13000491</pub-id>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Hunter2022">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Hunter</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Europe’s worst ever bird flu outbreak: Thus year’s epidemic of highly pathogenic avian flu has had a devastating impact on wild and domestic birds and severe economic consequences</article-title>
      <publisher-name>EMBO Reports</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="2022">2022</year>
      <volume>23</volume>
      <issue>10</issue>
      <uri>https://www.embopress.org/doi/full/10.15252/embr.202256048</uri>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Rigolon2018">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Rigolon</surname><given-names>Browning</given-names><suffix>A.</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Inequities in the quality of urban park systems: An environmental justice investigation of cities in the united states</article-title>
      <publisher-name>Landscape; Urban Planning</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="2018">2018</year>
      <volume>178</volume>
      <uri>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.landurbplan.2018.05.026</uri>
      <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.landurbplan.2018.05.026</pub-id>
      <fpage>156</fpage>
      <lpage>169</lpage>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-WHO2016">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Organization</surname><given-names>World Health</given-names></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Urban green spaces and health</article-title>
      <publisher-name>World Health Organization</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="2016">2016</year>
      <uri>https://iris.who.int/handle/10665/345751</uri>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-CWCB2021">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>CWCB</surname><given-names>DNR</given-names></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Colorado water plan</article-title>
      <publisher-name>CWCB</publisher-name>
      <uri>https://cwcb.colorado.gov/colorado-water-plan</uri>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ref-Williams2022">
    <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
      <person-group person-group-type="author">
        <name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>Cook</given-names><suffix>A. P.</suffix></name>
      </person-group>
      <article-title>Rapid intensification of the emerging southwestern north american megadrought in 2020–2021</article-title>
      <publisher-name>Nature Climate Change</publisher-name>
      <year iso-8601-date="2022">2022</year>
      <volume>12</volume>
      <uri>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41558-022-01290-z</uri>
    </element-citation>
  </ref>
</ref-list>
</back>

<!-- (F2ED4C6E)[nb-1]:C:\ESS330\git\Final-Project\setup.qmd -->

</article>